A Guide to the Executive Office Association Files of Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Executive Office: Association Files of Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2001
The Library of Virginia
40175
2 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1998-2002: Gilmore)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from James S. Gilmore, 17 November 2002.
Scope and Content
The records are comprised of briefing books (Governor James S. Gilmore's and his aides) for National Governors' Association Meetings between 1998 and 2001 and the Southern Governors' Association Meeting for 1998. The briefing books contain the meeting agenda and Governor's daily schedule for the meeting. They also may contain handwritten notes, prepared remarks, news clippings and press releases. Also included are several miscellaneous briefing books and reports that were interfiled with this series.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. National Governors' Association.
II. Southern Governors' Association.
III. Miscellaneous Briefing Books.
Contents List
- I. National Governors' Association, 1998-2001., Extent: 23 folders. (Box 1-2)
  - THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE GUIDE, 1996 November (part one) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE GUIDE, 1996 November (part two) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 1998 February 21-24, Washington, D.C. (part one) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 1998 February 21-24, Washington, D.C. (part 2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1998 August 1-4, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Mark Miner's copy) (part one) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1998 August 1-4, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Mark Miner's copy) (part two) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photo Album - Annual Meeting, 1998 August 1-4, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briefing Books - Winter Meeting, 1999 February 20-23, Washington, D.C. (Mark Miner's copy) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Media Clips - Winter Meeting, 1999 February 20-23, Washington, D.C. (Box 1, Folder 8a)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1999 August 7-10, St. Louis, Missouri (part one) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1999 August 7-10, St. Louis, Missouri (part two) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1999 August 7-10, St. Louis, Missouri (part three) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1999 August 7-10, St. Louis, Missouri (Mark Miner's copy) (part one) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1999 August 7-10, St. Louis, Missouri (Mark Miner's copy) (part two) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2000 February 26-29, Washington, D.C. (part one) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2000 February 26-29, Washington, D.C. (part two) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2000 February 26-29, Washington, D.C. (part three) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2000 February 26-29, Washington, D.C. (Mark Miner's copy) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 2000 July 8-11, State College, Pennsylvania (Lila White's copy) (part one) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 2000 July 8-11, State College, Pennsylvania (Lila White's copy) (part two) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2001 February 24-27, Washington, D.C. (part one) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book - Winter Meeting, 2001 February 24-27, Washington, D.C. (part two) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photo Album - Annual Meeting, 2001 August 4-7, Providence, Rhode Island (Box 2, Folder 3)
- II. Southern Governors' Association, 1998., Extent: 2 folders. (Box 2)
  - Briefing Book - Annual Meeting, 1998 August 30 - September 1, Dorado, Puerto Rico (Mark Miner's copy) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Briefing Book - Business Meeting, 1998 August 4, Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Mark Miner's copy) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- III. Miscellaneous Briefing Books, 1998-2000., Extent: 7 folders. (Box 2)
  - Progress Report: Uniform Accident Prevention Program State Owned Vehicles from Department of State Policy, 1997 June 30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Program for 1998 Governor's Executive Leadership Workshop, 1998 September 9, Richmond, Virginia (part one) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Program for 1998 Governor's Executive Leadership Workshop, 1998 September 9, Richmond, Virginia (part two) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Governor Gilmore's Briefing Book for Right Choices for Youth Conference, 1999 September 21 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia 2000 Federal Legislative and Regulatory Priorities prepared by Virginia Liaison Office (2000 March 6) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Exile, 2000 April (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Drug Free America Foundation, Inc., nd (Box 2, Folder 12)